hello welcome to this kind of
spontaneous riff with Cory Anton I'll
give some context in a second first some
housekeeping so one of the biggest
things going on is we just announced we
are going to be starting our first
circling practitioners training course
the other circling online information
down below and we also have a weekend
coming up this weekend I know that 16th
and 17th so not this weekend but the
following weekend on zoom' so please you
can click the lik links below also if
you're interested in working one-on-one
with me please email me and we could
talk about it alright so this video was
originally we were intending on and I'm
still intending on doing this of Cory's
written a bunch of books he's a
philosopher in media and communications
and ecology he's a professor at the
college and in Michigan and he's a an
old-time youtuber and I'm really really
liked him a lot he's a great guy we were
gonna initially do a series of
interviews of or dialogues about each
one of his books and we were gonna start
with selfhood in authenticity but
unfortunately because of some of the
timing issues we didn't really have
enough time to do that so we just ended
up getting out and spontaneously riffing
and we cover a lot a lot of things from
the coronavirus to cell cellular biology
to Elon Musk to phenomenology and
intelligibility and the incomprehensible
'ti of the earth and all the things that
he writes about and I like to think
about so enjoy and look forward to those
other videos with
Cory I'm gonna schedule that hopefully
for next week and we'll learn more about
his writing in his work I thank you yeah
I'm happy but I think this issue on the
lockdown its I would prefer to go to the
where exactly is the imposition on
people's freedoms I've yet to see it in
some way now the order to stay at home
that the governor is an issue that have
shut the businesses down
well now the governor's you know they're
working partly with the the companies
the corporations small businesses to get
those reopened so that when those people
are fearing for their lives they have to
quit rather than be fired or be laid off
because women because then they can't
collect insurance anymore then they
can't collect unemployment you know it's
like climate claims are going to be
different so there's there's some theory
there's a strange motive that's going on
there I think the shelter-in-place is
also you know the thing that I would
compare it to is the mask I heard some
people say well I'm not going to wear a
mask you know there's an imposition on
my rights
that's like well wait a second you know
if you're going to be angry about this
kind of stuff be angry with seatbelts
you know seatbelts those are an
imposition upon your right if you want
to die however you want to die well then
dot I without a seatbelt on and get
mangled when you have an accident and
maybe it's gonna be a little bit more
cost to hospitals into these Spencer he
becomes free beats up because you're
just you know that one's more damaged
but when you don't wear a mask
now you're risking other people's lives
it's like getting you had a car not have
a seatbelt on and closing your eyes
while you're driving yeah you have to go
bid not and people go well I don't have
professional masks at the point if you
just have like a half-baked mask only
like forty percent effective or fifty
percent and then other people have on a
half base mask have a pass of forty or
fifty percent effective it's not as if
we just have a forty or fifty percent
protection rate we're actually at about
eighty to ninety percent there yeah yeah
totally yeah and because there are so
many people who are asymptomatic and
carriers or people who are
pre-symptomatic who are carriers it's
just dangerous and I think you know
people don't people
not been following mr. getting all this
misinformation from the diet that Helen
was just completely confusing issues you
know I don't think it's going to be safe
to me elevators or in close quarters or
airplanes until there's something like
some kind of medical treatment yeah you
know if it's aerosolized it's maybe not
airborne but I think in the air for
anywhere between 20 minutes and three
hours depending upon the kind of
ventilation ready the outside you know
so if people if people get social
distance and they want to have a big
party and as long as it's outside and
it's windy and they're keeping distance
I think they're fine you can have a big
house parties where you're all three
than on each other in there's poor
ventilation you are a petri dish that
you're asking for trouble
mm-hmm yeah totally so the the so I
think what you're starting to speak to
is what I've kind of been thinking about
the corona crisis that the it it's it's
not that it's not the corona virus
that's causing the crisis the corona
virus is revealing the crisis yes well
it's the response it's it's the
narrative it's the overarching worldview
that it's his us exceptionalism denying
that he gutted out the you know the
pandemic response team in 2018 denying
that he sent 18 you know I think was 18
million tons of BP huge China
when they were in a crisis you don't
need to have a problem he wasn't paying
attention to memos he would golfy nine
times first hearing about it and
actually doing anything what's really to
do it nothing right I mean it's just
this ridiculous yeah you know he just
Pat's his own back and says oh he's so
great he takes more responsibility it's
really tragic I think this this is the
man talked about shooting up
disinfectants I mean if he had any
legitimate claim to being a critical
climate change and having some grounds
for disagreement in climates
it's gone this guy he doesn't know
scientific methodology or example yes
you can shoot up this infected
that's called embalming I mean alcohol
alcohol yes alcohol is a pretty
effective disinfectant you know why
because it's a sterilizer and in a
medical context its antiseptic it kills
everything it touches yeah yeah yeah
totally yeah hold it I mean yeah ten
shows up the Mayo Clinic without a mask
on use guys at the helm of the pandemic
response right right guys reading the
shots right right yes yes we're doomed
yeah we're doing out rebellion of people
going don't you tell me what to do why
don't you protest against seatbelts give
it a rest
and once you once you cheap outlaw is
corrected because that's an imposition
on your rights then maybe you realize
that here you're putting other people's
risk and otherwise at risk
Yeah right it's absurd man so I I think
that the fact is we don't have enough
information you look at Stanford
Stanford basically has been saying by
their tests by their estimates that it
could be anywhere between you know 40 or
50 or 60 maybe up to 80% of the
population has already added we had a
Harvard Harvard's like no there's hardly
any social penetration we're gonna have
to be in a lockdown until 2021 and then
you know what New York just had its most
recently did a random sample about 3,000
people they thought about 14% of New
York and maybe or 25% in New York City
but then there's all kinds of people we
don't really understand what the deal is
that some people are suggesting that
there is there are different strands and
there was like a kind of strain and that
came directly from China there was a
fairly mild one and that's what gives
the West Coast that's what getting to
Washington in California where is it
somehow when it hit Italy or Spain it
mutated it changed there was a different
viral load the people who came
more infectious on the well it was but
it is it's a different thing there yeah
it's a real different than shredders we
should keep or shedders yeah so we don't
even like we don't even know what that
difference is
there's just yeah mystery and
misinformation and one knows and the
answers but I mean I do I do think that
it's irritating that all the
intelligence agencies have said look
this is not man-made this is not a
weapon Trump continues to push the
conspiracy yeah yeah totally
here's the deal you know this many years
ago I had a really just a wonderful
invite from Dartmouth they brought me
out to the immunology team there's under
violent ships so Bob he contacted me
through you to make important I agree I
was interested and we had lots of
discussions and then he wanted to come
out to this immunology team and see if I
could help them in thinking about doing
either instructional material for them
or trying to think more about how to
graphically designed some of the stuff
I'm teaching people about the immune
system you know when I was younger I
thought that by I think not an arrogant
disrespect for biology but I think a
little bit you know I served well had
physics Envy was like wow the physicists
they really know and you can chemists I
was like wow you know the organic
chemistry tricky stuff but the
biologists don't like oh let me guess
the knee bone is connected to the shin
bone where desolately bones there are
you know I learned more about physiology
and I thought wow you know physiologies
pretty tough like when I went and
learned about the immune system and not
only sizzled my brain and realized this
was well behind me what was I was really
humbled into you know I think the immune
system is infinitely more complex than
any of us understand and because of that
it's so prone to conspiracy yeah yeah
and you just as it has no genetic makeup
you have a memory and then your blood
type matters in the conditions matter
like the difference between cholera and
a virus is huge and whether or not you
have old blood type or a blood type of
man there's all these different
variables
it's a sea of complexity rest in your
bodies yes
no no it's yeah yeah and depending on
where you slice it which is depends on
where you're coming from
but but then you add in then you add in
the evolutionary aspect of it and then
you're just that stuff is just you ever
seen that you've you ever seen that
movie about the way the way genes
separate where they do a 3d animation
have you seen that once a TED talk I
think it was first done when they go a
reit video a real like a scaled
unzipping it and they watch how this it
is it is absolutely it is so miraculous
it's so incredible it hurts - it
literally hurts to watch yeah and I have
no idea what you know I loved your video
oh yeah Nora yeah ignore a lot you know
I met her once
[Music]
yeah I think you Lynn Margulis and
Dorion Sagan but many books that they
have done in microbiology
what is life or symbiotic planet or
microcosms you know these are just
amazing books where you know I think a
lot of people the public in general you
know they were shocked
I mean just shocked to hear the claim
that humans were descendants from
monkeys they're not ready to hear that
we're descendants from cannibalistic
bacteria when you do the really big
argument is you know I mean you know
death was a sexually transmitted disease
sources yeah it's it's it's interesting
it's if you want to watch people's
ideologue go away just get get true
about what's going on biologically I
mean it's just it's absolutely socially
completely like politically incorrect on
every side almost every dimension yeah
almost to the point where I know that is
it weinstein talks about like he
he hasn't been able to have a true
biologic like a biological conversation
in public in years because it's people's
can't hear it because their ideologue
right which i think is whatever that is
is part of what you're talking about
yeah I mean I do think you know the
unsustainability of all of this it's
really hard for any of us to accept it I
think we want to believe I think part of
the fascination with Silicon Valley and
with robots and the super technology
technological future its to hide as much
as we can from the utters
unsustainability yeah yeah yeah totally
totally and this is where it gets to I
mean this is where it does get to you
know in a strange way the very thing
that allows us to glimpse into like
organisms and in DNA and you know this
ayat like the whole scientific
revolution that allowed us to be able to
see like this is in some meta way also
the very thing that that also seems to
be tied to put like a lot of the ways
that we don't actually see the whole of
it as well
right this kind of thing where where
this you know this whole especially what
do you think of this this whole thing
about like transhumanism yes you know
I'm I'm very skeptical one of my most
recent publications was uh Isaac's I
generally do celebratory scholarship I
like to find scholars oh I'm into and
I'm studying meteor big in Stein or I'm
all into de Rd or Lynn Margulis and I'm
learning I'm drilling I try to
synthesize and just cuz I'm one of the
very very few critical pieces I've ever
written it was recently I did a fairly
brutal critique of David levees were the
guy who wrote love and sex with robots
kind of eating chess champion ooh he was
interviewed by Scientific American in
2008 basically saying that
mid-century sex with robots and marriage
with robots was going to be mainstream
and you know that they're they're gonna
be superior as mates and lovers and
almost got stuff I thought this is the
biggest horseshit I think I've ever seen
you know so I'm very very skeptical I
would consider myself a deep skeptic
okay I you know I think Kurzweil is an
interesting cat you know is there a
singularity sure I think we're gonna
become cyborgs we're gonna win Ghent
we're gonna inject nanobots we're gonna
swallow the Google pill we're gonna put
in implants but we're not gonna ever
invent something like data you're not
gonna have Blade Runner you're not gonna
have the ex machina where there's some
cyborg organism robot that you know is
kind of doesn't know that it's a robot
Jersey ex machina no I don't think so
yeah I've been watching all the old
because we're in lockdown and we're
trying to you know amplify the surreal
nosov it all or at least would be equal
to report we've been watching all of the
old Twilight zones they're so great
because it's like Howard you know it's
just crazy yeah but they're so surreal
and there's a good number of them that
are on artificial intelligences and
robots and yeah you know I'm I'm very
very skeptical like Sophia you follow
Sophia so enhancing robotic says
basically a publicity stunt that came
out of Saudi Arabia the Saudi Arabia's
trying to distance itself from oil and
demonstrate that it's a leader in
technology this thing Sophia you know
gives a press conference releases it
needs her dignitaries and talks gives
lectures and stuff what did you start
this adventure with stop it is three
different operating software's one of
which is basically a lifetime script
editor that amounts to making it a
ventriloquist all it does have a chat
but sort of like so like Alexa this kind
of stuff and then it has OpenCog which
is supposedly this self-teaching you
know open source you know an AGI is an
artificial general country it's all
bullshit it's a so I introduced where
they were like you know so Sophie is a
citizen in Saudi Arabia
what does it citizen mean what was a
citizenship mean they what do you mean
he goes what what exactly does that
amount to like house innocence and I was
insistent you network is Italy and they
go well she's a citizen they go well
when when she flies somewhere to take to
give a talk where does she sit in the
plane I mean does she pay for her fare
the she shouldn't first-class one they
go although we throw in the cargo bay
yeah totally yeah well I mean it also
just gets to this thing that you just
can't compute consciousness like it's
it's it has it just shows I think it
does culminate this kind of Cartesian
viewpoint right this whole thing about
calculation and you know finding the
code and in that it seems like we're a
lot of actually interesting things with
AI starts to come up is with is is
through robotics right it's gonna it's
like it's it's it's in the interaction
with the world right which is a lot of
actually what your your your your book
with the authenticity really gets that
right we've ever really treated her
what's that your movie her no oh yeah oh
yeah yes in the right direction
am at this is very this like this or a
kind of garyun moment to sort of it
especially for like huge like this or
Raymond Callahan with the talisman some
of the best petites a drag this is one
way they could keep so sort of the
promise of AI yes you know like imagine
just for argument's sake that there is
this super supreme intelligence that can
calculate things at ten thousand times
my speed
can read 400 books in an evening who
doesn't have to sleep why what exactly
would its participants like I have to go
to bed at night and there it stays up
all night it's read a hundred books it
sees me in the morning now how is it
fucking relation to me isn't he changed
as a board shitless with the passage of
time something that has speeds at that
rate it like experience in eternity
right right totally but that's what
happened in that movie right yeah I
loved it when I loved I loved the part
when and I'm surprised they were able to
pull it off at the end of the movie when
was Alan Watts pull that off without it
being totally cheesy she ex machina
that's really an interesting discussion
that's that's a fascinating one because
I think it deals with this issue of the
Turing test you know I think part of the
reason well here's what I'd say paper I
could send if you want this yes please
but it's I think what happened was he in
the fifties and forties and fifties and
then by the time I guess modern
psychology came along they went out for
dinner but then the a I even had I've
been in Cedar became the poster child
does the robot can be caring that is
Gary there is no such thing as care
other than the behavior of care yeah and
you know I think that was that was a
huge I guess
trend within within the yeah well here's
a it's like but here's the thing that's
interesting is
I think one of the things that you bring
out a lot what I got through actually
reading your book which is for people
who are watching and we're gonna we're
gonna do it we're gonna do it we're
gonna do this but the timing issues
we're gonna go over your book which I'm
really excited about doing but one of
the things that you really I really got
out of that was this thing that you
talked about in your in your chapter
about sociality like the social negation
of the way that the world like the like
the way that you can appropriate the
world or would want to and how built in
past relations right start to bring
confines into what you can't do what you
can't appropriate and where you can
write in that in that this this sense of
like and I and I noticed that like if
you really want to know because we used
to do this to help people kind of break
out of like social shame or reveal
social shame is just imagine what it'd
be like to go into a Starbucks and just
lay on the floor right it'd be you start
to like you reveal the not right but
what's interesting is that is that
because it isn't we relate to it by
actually it's infused in standing in
line at Starbucks and doing the various
things that are appropriate right and so
like this this sense about the the not
like how you could get like something to
appropriate or even grasp right like in
terms of consciousness about what's be
able to relate to what something is it
is something that just I've heard being
around a lot of people in the Bay Area
right who are working on a I've heard
them talk about like that's one of the
biggest dilemmas is that you can't come
no one's been able to figure out how you
get a computation to relate to what what
they're not what it's not like that
whole thing is seems to be very key to
your book pages terms it's very related
to the logic
there there are different lots of you
tighten to fake orders of abstraction or
those have to can be like play phrase
and so you know one of the ways that we
learn what is in the set in what's not
in the set isn't play and you know so
yeah I mean just in the terms that you
know in the book I would say that yeah
there's the body has various capacities
were released in an appropriation it's
sort of like someone is a tiny hearing
but this early and yeah there are filled
intentions and they're empty cages so if
I say to you you know let's talk about
Amsterdam if either of us have ever been
to Amsterdam we're like okay well maybe
have a sense that we've seen pictures of
what we heard the words the intention is
more than empty whereas if you actually
been to Amsterdam afraid you have more
filled intentions because you physically
have released an appropriated certain
aspects of that suite with your own
sensory capacities you know so like
you've been answering at my been
answered and you know like Antonia brief
drives an amazing place to be is a great
road or if you go to like damn 307 cool
coffee shop with a three in the middle
of it and to see yourself is to have
released an appropriate it is our
primary way talking about but then as
you suggest that one of the things of
our reality is that our lives are never
just ours that were personal partly
social through and through and so the
release and appropriation is socially
orchestrated and regulated there's a
kind of orchestration and regulation
about what one does and what one doesn't
do know this is an ID here's boss Bob
you know it's about the de self and this
construction of orderliness in the world
and yeah I mean I think the what I say
there the the dynamic of of avoiding
where you know you're not welcome and
not bringing up certain topics with
people because you know it would make
them uncomfortable
now think things that you don't want
them to think yeah it's sort of orders
then it's sort of similar to the chess
move let me see my critique they've let
me that I try to do this robots paper
which is you know it's one thing to say
here is a chessboard and here are
probability fields or what is the likely
best move
given the current position of the pieces
and you know I can see your perspective
in mind and might there's some history
about your playing strategy but there's
basically a probability field with a
bunch of statistics about best possible
moves that's very very different than
something quite simple which is I'm at a
cocktail party and there's like five
people and we're having a discussion
about how much I spent on a bottle of
wine and we're gonna ask whether or not
I nice with my money or I'm stingy with
my life see in the real world of your
subjectivity we have to deal with the
sense of some people think I'm stingy
and some people think that I'm my scent
just some people think I'm about right
and I have to know well this person
thinks absolutely this person thinks I
and I sort of deal with that any
strategy of AI is to basically create
the algorithm which answers are you
stingy or aren't you totally in that and
like how you appropriate that for
yourself is is gonna be a constant
activity I don't think you ever do
really I mean you may have somebody that
can kind of say say that like a
proposition but it's mostly like the way
in which we are embodied and related we
are constantly being closed shaped and
shaping
yes yes and so I say a buzzline or river
from the book is that others are a
condition of our existence not a feature
of our experience again others are a
condition of our existence they're not a
feature in our experience I think me
think like like I'm looking here I see
you over there and I'm over here
and I think of authors as these objects
in my visual field or in my experiences
where actually I've come to
self-conscious existence only through
others I didn't name myself I wasn't
that English I was basically taught
speaking English and very English as the
mode of my own self-consciousness to
come to myself so others have already
infected me into the deepest recesses
that they are the distance which I've
done to myself
yeah haunted haunted haunted is ignore
mean I think this is one lakhan's major
insight is that intersubjectivity
precede subjectivity yeah I mean there's
no means when he would have called it
eccentric I mean certainly we are
organisms that have electricity but the
kind of transcendent there's a
transcendence it's built into life
itself with respiration of metabolism
with the senses of the body of a
multicellular organism those offer
arabica transcendence and then by the
time you get to language of discourse
and communication technologies is stored
and grounded technologies like the
alphabet our calendars applies now
you're having this radical radical
experience of you're not in space and
time like an organism that's just
located with its senses in the immediate
ear and now you're a social historical
being who knows something like it's 2020
and that it's May and that there is this
thing called mother's being coming up
and we're social historical world yeah
there's a yes so there's a way that we
are the whole thing about is it some
note is that how you say it summers
Easter yes yeah yeah that that that
sense I really like the way that that
sense kind of goes through all the
different ways that you can appropriate
of where I think you were talking about
it like this this great language so
where things I like about this level of
dialogue right is that is is it's not
just it's not just being informed like
in order to
understand what you're saying in your
book you actually have to see the thing
and use that which you're you you're
like it there's this way where it's
fractal like - it's like you um in the
beginning of every chapter you almost
have these almost like like : questions
right about like like about language and
about hearing and about seeing that are
kind of an IgG Matic and then you go on
and you don't answer them you just it's
you well you kind of do answer them but
but but how you go about it is it you go
and you address what those questions
presuppose right and you show the
metaphysics of those propositions and
then by the time that you go like you
walk around through what is it that
we've considered hearing up to this
point what is the the smuggled and right
assumptions about materialism or you
know about social constructionism and
then you start to work all that out and
then by the end of it it's like you
didn't necessarily answer the question
but you have a completely new question
that you could ask and you're on a new
kind of place to stand on right where
you realizing that that question like a
lot of those questions presupposed so
many things that were invisible to us
right and something about making those
visible and demonstrating them and
showing how the mistake actually does
point to the like the limitation of that
the question presupposes ray points to a
truth about the phenomena that you could
address there's something about making
that walk back and then kind of seeing
it newly likes like things kind of
flailing open that is it's it's it's a
it I feel like I've like that kind of
thinking and reading this stuff has
really kind of changes the way that you
see it changes the way that you think
right we just go back to what you said
at the very beginning I mean I really
agree that's right I think phenomenology
as a method is basically learning on a
beginner dies it's very honest see
things as if you were
and non-native it's it's somehow doing
away and coming back and taking the trip
that allows things that are already
familiar to seem unfamiliar enough you
can sort of see them and yeah I mean I
think in some way if anyone wanted to
understand my book they would be much
better off to set the book down to
really look at themselves and see what
shows itself to ask themselves what it
means to think what it needs to have a
body but it needs to be conversation
with others and and then really try to
focus on their experience their
existence is the larger flame for their
experiences with energy things and then
knowing that I'm trying to describe that
yeah look at the book as an attempted
description of what they're directly
experience you're directly experiencing
and see how you can try to get a
language for describing patterns and
regularities well this I think is what
I'm saying is like in reading your book
I end up back there looking out of it in
order to understand what you just said
that's the thing that's really I've been
trying to bring words to what that is I
mean I think what are the things that
people you know people like zigs at
Mohali I'm slow you know there's so much
stuff on athletes who learn to get in
the flow and get in the zone I think we
underestimate how much I mean that's
true it's good advice what did it be
underestimate how much we're perpetually
continuously forgetting about ourselves
and losing ourselves in the landscape
it's from one engagement to the next
we're sort of there than were aware of
ourselves and then sure enough we forgot
that were there and were lost in
whatever dispersed around us indication
like what day of the week is it or what
it's happening at the microcosm it's
happening in conversations it's just
but we normally recessed we're normally
the absence which is the rule making for
everything else
it's reflection that we think were there
in addition to the yeah yeah with the
way the world works the world's world
EGF was momentary senses where we said
Oh lion here wait a second
you've always been there but you forgot
about yourself yeah absolutely
in fact hold on you're I got a ok you
got it
well it's you know one of the things to
you I mean we'll go to this deeper and a
next conversation too but like your
thing that in fact I highlighted all the
poor all the all the places that you
talked about this where you talk about
the Earth's internal negating it's
non-existence right and it it's on one
level that's so fucking bizarre to think
about right but on another level it's
you it's like if there's anything that I
felt like kind of deepened through the
whole thing it was this sense of this
sense of this that I am we are the earth
right doing something in that in that if
you in a lot of ways a lot the you know
a lot of your book to is is a
conversation with you know materialism
and social constructionism and
post-modernism in your you actually
address some things that have bugged me
a lot about some of that stuff which is
but it seems like how you do it is you
start to restore a sense of ground right
to to that and I think how you do that
is through this this conversation about
the earth what how is it the light I
think you know for my own lights I mean
basically what happened it's an
oversimplification but was was Cyril had
created an amazing body of phenomena
sport
and then tiger and Sartre and really Oh
Ponty pulled that out in a certain way
well Alfred shoots Alfred shirts was a
student of wood sorrel
shoots in disagreement Sartre in kind of
an alignment with with with the literal
believed in a transcendental Sartre did
not I'm an agreeable Sartre here and and
I think you can do you know basically
use personal against himself to show
that longitudinal functionalities are
able to do everything that he was trying
to do people like Alfred shoulds
basically that part of the sural that
was grounded in the transcendental ego
he'd been with Thomas lumpy wrote a good
number of books on social construction
of reality Thomas not been then got
together with Peter Berger and they
wrote the book on social construction of
reality the social structures the
tradition particularly as it came out of
Vermont history existential turn and
they tried to make reality constructed
out of language rather than this
phenomenological grounding of a body in
a sociology it's a party constitutive of
language for me this is where we keep
things in the book that isn't really
said in the book but supplied in the
book of the sort of I was really trained
and this is my doctoral dissertation
basically what I was trained in you know
phenomenology hermeneutics and it's
about the inner meeting of things and so
you know it begins with the boosters and
the knockers of Taylor's work you know
where Taylor was trying to say what
there's a sponsor of authenticity of the
license to live your own life and some
people are for it so people are against
it it has to do positive interpretations
which I want to say yeah we're all
probably leave suddenly late comers to
the party this thing happened at least
couple hundred years ago but now if
we're going to say there is a call to
authenticity well what exactly is this
self Anniston well and so for me as i
was trying to say before that there is
at least i'm embodied i'm social i'm so
nurus
or linguistic or communicative and then
temporal and that you can understand any
one of those by seen how it's
constituted by the other
an embodiment you're gonna have to show
that you come from other people and that
you're 12 it's social your sociality run
so much deeper than culture I mean your
biological mother of your kin
the same thing with all of our concepts
you know are going to distinguish
ourselves from others it comes from
language when you try to really get at
sociology owners in temporarily what is
temporality will jump reality is some
for at least for multicellular organism
such as ourselves it's some
configuration of embodiment sociality
and yeah yeah yeah that ni it felt it
felt like he got really in the guts of
that like that I thought really well in
that sense of I think you used the term
what is that the the intention the
intend oh and the intend of onus right
right there's the seeing there's this it
like the the seeing the scene and the
seeable miss and that you it was in the
feebleness that like happens you really
showed how like it happens in between
you can't reduce it to one or the other
but there's this relationship and so one
of the things that that thing about the
earth like what for you where does that
come from like like on one level there's
a I mean you taco it's such a it's such
a rich thing to think about but like
literally the world by coming out of
another he says just as a tree flowers
Sony Earth people and then people world
so and there's this
the earth does people need and the
people are world over bodies roll out of
other bodies that have emerged out of
various levels of microbiotic symbiosis
and then all of that it has social
historical Constitution you know in the
human realm what we're experiencing
right now isn't what it needs to be
human we're experiencing what minds can
be made given all kinds of social
historical conditions and communication
technologies right separable from who we
are yeah yeah and it's just this this
idea about like I remember as I was I
was um as I was read it as a reading it
and I was going for walks I go like
three or four walks a day you know well
I well I'm locked down and make myself
crazy but the I was walking along after
recently and I just looking around and I
just had this sense of just almost like
rather than a bunch of things that I'm
looking at just it all kind of one being
one fabric right and then the people
walking next to me were like little
little like small openings like talking
to each other that then were given and
reflected to the houses that built up
and all of the in it just like imagining
like the darkening like the darkness of
earth somehow negating itself and then
watching it has this to really grok it
was you could kind of get this sense
about I mean I think I think the sense
of earthly gating it's not existence
that I did in 2006
heidegger's notion of death as an
adequate account for individuation out
of gas I lost in Lhasa today so and I
try to do a lot of stuff on between the
sleep and I think is the example I you
know if you want to get at what I mean
by the non-existence of Earth its
dreamless sleep that's what dreamless
sleep is that's Perth non-existent when
you wake up that's Earth negating its
non-existence
yeah yeah totally
I think some of this too is brown that's
my motion book is much more grounded
this microbiotic science that i think i
think my senior students do you really
go here soon hopefully I won't get
people thrown yet but I think you know
one must know his plane you know maybe
he wants to go to Mars by 2025 anything
else good stuff
I'd love to say to students all kinds of
things like this that first off that
you've never ever in your entire life
sucked any fluid up a straw no don't
know what you do is you put your mouth
around the straw you lower the
atmospheric pressure mind having your
diaphragm go down then the atmosphere
pushes the fluid up the straw into your
mouth stored under yeah look at the
amount of weight-bearing exercise that
astronauts have to do when they're in
weightlessness you have to do hours
worth of weightlifting every day to keep
your bones from ossifying brain there's
brain distortions when you don't have
that same sort of magnetic field you
don't have the same atmospheric pressure
like there you're never gonna have a
baby come to a full term pregnancy and
we not gonna have a full term pregnancy
it was a little baby that different
weights in there can keep its dual
answer sighs I'm sorry to tell you how
muscular earthling we're never leaving
for places and moments on this planet
I'm sorry that they have faces because
they came from other continents they
came to another comment an explorer is
deep inside us that is delusional maybe
there's been people lots we're gonna
gallivant around what people are never
leaving sober up and take care of this
planet is best you can that's where
we're at right right totally
[Laughter]
wealthy it has some good ideas doesn't
mean you're a genius about everything no
let's see he's not a smart guy
people just listen to the wealthy people
as if somehow if you're wealthy you must
be smart right right right
totally well it's also I think it's it's
it's there's a there's an element of
where it's particularly and even notice
it's quickened it like the smart like
the people who are wealthy and smart now
are more and more tech like they're more
and more engineer tech like orientation
right and I think and we can talk a lot
about that I mean I'm Ally I mean I'm in
the Bay Area so I'm I'm I'm and I have
I've worked a lot with people who are
very worried about AI like very worried
about AI and like it in the sense not in
the sense of AI as in its gonna have
consciousness it in the sense of that
you know the moment that it's able to
produce itself right and all of the all
of the things essentially like what we
can't account for right so just like if
we were to release a virus and into this
we have no you know as Bateson would say
we don't have any because we don't see
the intimate integrity right of the
earth we can't relate to it right you
don't really really are I don't think
you see ourselves as ancient yeah part
of the biome that have accumulated all
kinds of microbiotic relation or about
the micro but like like the living room
and flame right people just be the I
fools them they trust what they see they
don't understand the multi level
interconnectivity stuff life I mean I
think I was starting to see a little bit
of it with the food chain disruption but
yeah complexities of what we're able to
experience and how it's a social
historical event interweaving you know I
think again I I could be wrong I'm happy
to say I could be wrong I think that
we're never gonna leave the people who
duly
they're gonna die you're gonna die short
live on Mars Mars yeah what are you
gonna do that you can't get along you
shouldn't go to Mars okay just talk
about nothing there talk about no
resources talk about just a new
situation yeah your body I think we
think the body is a thing you don't
realize that the body is an offense
that's caught in interconnected
Malaysian mean you trying to get it you
know that's why they age I guess you
know I'm not just a thing in space I'm
actually aging you really start to think
about it no year eight microbiotic soon
you're you're a very complicated zoo
legs totally in that indigenous sense of
going through something right like if
it's hard to comprehend and I think we
took a huge leap within the in with
phones and computers and you know it's
exponential you know the amount that's
available to us that we are not even
aware that we're not going through in
order to have all of that right there
right when we wake up in the morning and
and because we don't have to go through
it we find ourselves in our phones and
then we don't notice how we it fashions
how we think right and so like you just
add on so a few generations to that and
then you have the heroes being like you
know these kind of autistic let's go to
Mars and these kind of computational
things that may miss a lot of the
intelligibility of what it is
essentially what it is what it is to
that how one develops character right
just there's somebody really the same
position you're doing good social
distancing I try to you don't even know
the meaning it's social distance
this look like a party yeah totally
totally good good hanging out with you
will also join with you over email
yeah let's do it let's do a little
formally into the book I'll actually
even write up some questions a jury or a
tea here